Alexander Smith

ABOUT

I've been interested in front end web development for a number of years. Only recently have I sought out professional training specifically for web development. What I love about web development is the user experience. It's what I think about anytime I interact with a ui. The two most important questions I ask when I participate in the development of any ui are: Does it facilitate a positive, intuitive, and accessible user experience? And does it look good?

EXPERIENCE

Software QA

Focused Support LLC, Logan UT | April 2019 - PRESENT

Tools and Skills

Git, Docker, Selenium(Java), Atlassian Suite, Zephyr for Jira.

Responsibilities

Exploratory testing. Test/verify new features and bug fixes. Report bugs and determine bug priority. Regression test before release. Help resolving design concerns. Write automation tests.

Software QA

Space Dynamics Lab, Logan UT | February 2018 - December 2018

Tools and Skills

Git, SQL, Shell Scripting, Atlassian Suite, Test Documentation, Selenium(C#), Visual Studio.

Responsibilities

Manual test, Regression test, writing automated selenium tests, lots of test documentation.

Junior Web developer

MicroFocus, Provo UT | September 2016 - May 2017

Tools and Skills

HTML, CSS, Laravel(PHP), Javascript, OpenText Teamsite, Wordpress, Excel.

Responsibilities

Mostly building static pages. Bug fixes throughout the site. Some Javascript and Laravel.

Web Development Internship

EKR, Provo | April 2014 - September 2014

Tools and Skills

HTML, CSS, Magenta, Wordpress.

Responsibilities

Basic Testing. Content stuffing and management.

EDUCATION

Web Programming and Development

Mountainland Technical | August 2019 - PRESENT

Computer Science

Utah State University | January 2017 - January 2019

SKILLS

HTML	5	CSS		5
Selenium	4	Attla	ssian	4
Git	3	Javas	script	3
Node.js	2	Reac	t	1
Angular	1	Туре	escript	1
SQL	2	Mon	goDB	1
Docker	2	AWS		1
1 - Basics		3 - Proficient	5 -	Experienced